ROMAN **LEONOVICH**

Saint-Petersburg, Russia ↑ +79502275367 ****

Roma.a.leon@gmail.com ✓

Telegram: @romichxd

github.com/romichxd



ML ENGINEER/DATA SCIENTIST

I have been interested in programming since I finished my school in 2014. Since then I have started learning programming languages, algorithms, structures e.t.c. My first programming language was C++, then I started learning some of the web related languages as JavaScript (along with HTML and CSS), and Java. In total I have worked with C++, C#, JavaScript, Python, 1C and Java.

My "best" languages are C++, R, Python and Java.

I have been studying statistics static modelling and machine learning so I'm planning to develop myself in this sphere.



EDUCATION

Bachelor in applied mathematics and computer science | Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping

2016 - 2020

I have my bachelor's degree with GPA 4.9 out of five. During my education, I was nominated as "The best student" in 2018. My bachelor's research paper was written on medical diagnosis using static methods and neural networks.

Master in applied mathematics and computer science | Saint-Petersburg State University

2020 - 2022

Now I am getting my master's degree in computer science and learning about static modelling and regression analysis.

English level – C1: https://certs.duolingo.com/pe4k4fks



EXPERIENCE

- Tutor (math, programming, English) [2017-2020]
- Intern in data collection (audio) [2021-2022]
- Academic research using regression models, discriminant analysis and neural networks
 [2019-2021]



PROJECTS

My machine learning projects started when I was working on a bachelor paper. I've been constructing neuro network, logistic regression and discriminant analysis models and comparing them in diagnosing diseases. As I started my master's program I continued my work and used symptom analysis to increase accuracy of these model as well as experimenting with data.

In university there was some classes related to Big Data and Data Mining so I've been learning such things as decision trees, boosting, deep learning, handwriting recognition and e.t.c



- Problem Solving
- Communication

- Empathy
- Leadership
- Adaptability



Besides programming, I am interested I have other hobbies such as playing the guitar and piano and going to the gym. I also like to spend my free time with my friends and I always seek for opportunities to meet new people.